Mss.Ms.Coll.95 Mss.Ms.Coll.95
American Philosophical Society
Floyd Glenn Lounsbury papers, ca. 1935-1998
Circa 1935-1998
Mss.Ms.Coll.95
American Philosophical Society
90.0 Linear feet
The papers contain correspondence, research and teaching notes, data (card and slip) files, published and unpublished manuscripts by Lounsbury and others, books and reprints, sound recordings, and computer programs and files. Correspondents include: William N. Fenton, Mary R. Haas, William C. Sturtevant, Morris Swadesh, and Carl F. Voegelin. Roughly one-quarter of the collection relates to Iroquoian languages and includes much WPA Oneida Project material. Research into the Cherokee language, South American languages, and kinship structures is also well represented. Floyd Lounsbury's wife, Masako Yokoyama Lounsbury, is represented by a smaller amount of material relating to linguistic research in Shanghai.
90 linear feet.
Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
Haas, Mary R., (Mary Rosamond), 1910-1996
Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
Sturtevant, William C.
Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
Voegelin, C.F. (Charles Frederick), 1906-1986
Box 1-240
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Presented by Ruth Ozeki Lounsbury, 1998.
Biographical/Historical note
A Wisconsin native, Lounsbury completed his undergraduate education at the University of Wisconsin - Madison, and took an MA degree there. He then went to Yale University and was awarded a Ph.D. for work on Oneida phonology and morphology in 1949. While in the Ph.D. program he started teaching, and remained at Yale for the rest of his career. Retiring in 1979, Lounsbury was appointed Sterling Professor Emeritus of Anthropology, a post he held until his death at age 84.
Influenced by his graduate advisor, Morris Swadesh, Lounsbury undertook (1939-1940) the WPA-funded Oneida Language and Folklore Project, Green Bay, Wisconsin. This work eventually culminated in his MA thesis and dissertation. Lounsbury undertook pioneering work in descriptive and comparative Iroquoian linguistics, and made very significant contributions to the decipherment of Maya hieroglyphic texts. He was also an important innovator in the formal analysis of kinship terminologies and structural semantics. Fieldwork was conducted among the Oneida and all other speakers of surviving Iroquoian languages, Natchez, two Mayan and six Brazilian Indian languages. Lounsbury was a fellow of the National Academy of Sciences (1969), and a member of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences (1976) and American Philosophical Society (1987).
Scope and Contents note
Works by Lounsbury are found in multiple series, throughout the collection.
Native American Images note: Just over 1,200 black and white photomechanical prints; black and white silver gelatin photographs; color, ink, and pencil sketches; and color illustrations of Mayan glyphs and Inca ethnological images from 1958-1995. Collected by Lounsbury to support his linguistic research, glyphic prints are from Mayan codices and stelae. In works by others, the South American series includes images of Inca calendars, Waimiri-Atroari Indian customs, and Quechua pottery from the Andes region. Of note, the Dresden Codex contains glyphs reproduced from the original color tracings. Check the inventory with detailed descriptions of each folder.
Conditions Governing Access note
Recommendations and Evaluations (2 linear feet) are restricted.
Cherokee language; Gelatin silver prints; Illustrations--Color; Incas--Social life and customs; Indians of Central America--Languages--Writing; Indians of Mexico--Languages--Writing; Indians of South America--Andes Region--Social life and customs; Indians of South America--Languages; Iroquoian languages; Lacandon Indians--Social life and customs; Maps.; Mayan languages--Writing; Oneida Indians; Oneida Indians--Wisconsin; Oneida language; Photomechanical prints; Quechua Indians--Social life and customs; Sketches.; United States. Works Progress Administration; Waimiri Indians--Social life and customs
- Series I. Correspondence (Box 1-18)
  - Aaron, Ely M., 1950; 3 items (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Material in support of a claim to the Indian Claims Commission on behalf of the Indian Tribe of Wisconsin.
  - Abbott, Clifford, 1974-1998; 24 items (Box 1)
    Abbott's work on Oneida. Mentions FGL's work on Tuscarora. Enclosures missing.
  - Aberle, David F., 1953-1970; 3 items (Box 1)
    Aberle's analysis of kinship in "Canadian" material.
  - Aberle, Kathleen, 1969; 2 items (Box 1)
    Student and faculty strike at Simon Fraser University.
  - Abler, Thomas S., 1990; 1 item (Box 1)
    Notes on Elizabeth Tooker's comments on Seneca kinship. Enclosure missing.
  - Acoustical Society of America, 1950; 1 item (Box 1)
    Publication of papers from a Speech Communication Conference and membership application.
  - Acuna, Rene, 1980; 1 item (Box 1)
    A Motul (Mayan) dictionary.
  - Adam, Herbert, 1970; 6 items (Box 1)
    Two copies of a response to Kathleen Aberle's article "The Struggle at Simon Fraser University."
  - Adams, Richard N., 1963-1970; 12 items (Box 1)
    Inviting FGL to visit the University of Texas, Austin, to speak and talk with students; students interested in jobs at UT; Chorti (Mayan) consultant at Yale; possibility of FGL teaching in Rio de Janeiro.
  - Adams, Robert McC., 1980; 1 item (Box 1)
    Description of the purpose of the Committee on Basic Research in the Behavioral and Social Sciences and a request for comments by FGL.
  - Adams, Thomas R., 1964-1965; 5 items (Box 1)
    Fellowships available from the John Carter Brown Library, Brown University (enclosures missing) and Quechua materials in the library.
  - Ainsworth, Jerry L., 1991; 2 items (Box 1)
    Request for the meaning of some Maya glyphs from Mexico. Includes drawing of the glyphs.
  - Alatis, James E., 1961-1965; 5 items (Box 1)
    Preparation of instructional materials in Quechua; grant proposal to produce teaching materials in Yucatec and Quiche (Mayan).
  - Albert, Ethel M., 1961-1964; 4 items (Box 1)
    Status of FGL's article for Educational Resources in Anthropology Project; request for reference for NSF fellowship.
  - Alcina, Jose, 1964; 2 items (Box 1)
    FGL's article for the Acts of the XXXVI International Congress of Americanists.
  - Alcock, F.J., 1953; 2 items (Box 1)
    Forwarding to FGL notes by Marius Barbeau on 6 Iroquoian dialects.
  - Aliphat Fernandez, Mario M., 1992; 4 items (Box 1)
    An international colloquium on Maya archaeology.
  - Alland, Alex, 1962; 2 items (Box 1)
    Alland's work in the Rep. Ivory Coast, West Africa.
  - Allen, Bill, [1976]; 1 item (Box 1)
    FGL's talk at Wesleyan, taking Loundsbury's course in Mayan hieroglyphics; offprints.
  - Alpher, Barry, 1988; 1 item (Box 1)
    Gender marking on mixed-sex, non-singular subjects in Iroquoian (Enclosure missing)..
  - Altamirano, Oscar, 1964-1966; 4 items (Box 1)
    Altamirano's work on Quechua; job possibilities.
  - Alverson, Hoyt S., 1965-1971; 9 items (Box 1)
    FGL's illness; Alverson's predoctoral fellowship; time-sharing applications in anthropology at Dartmouth College.
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1985; 4 items (Box 1)
    Nomination and election of members.
  - American Anthropological Association, 1951-1991, n.d.; 31 items (Box 1)
    FGL's membership status; AAA publications; his election as an AAA fellow; AAA meetings; visiting lecturer program; review of manuscripts; FGL's 1990 Distinguished Lecture.
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1959; 3 items (Box 1)
    Membership in AAAS as member of American Ethnological Society.
  - American Bible Society, 1950; 2 items (Box 1)
    Christian scriptures in Aymara and Quechua.
  - American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS) (Box 1)
    - American Council of Learned Societies, 1946-1972; 93 items (Box 1)
      FGL's time in Brazil while in the Army; returning to school; work on Oneida and Cherokee; fellowships and reports; Committee on Language Programs; linguistics; etc.
    - Joint Committee on American Native Languages, 1945-1965, n.d.; 270 items (Box 1)
      Membership of the committee; activities of the committee; proposed research projects. Includes a 1934 letter from Franz Boas to Manuel J. Andrade.
    - Program in Oriental Languages, 1953-1961, n.d.; 132 items (Box 1)
      Correspondence primarily with Masako Lounsbury, somewhat with FGL regarding the preparation, review, revising, and publication of instructional materials, Spoken Shanghai. Correspondents include: Yuen-Ren Chao, Charles F. Hockett, John Kepke, Fang-Kuei Li, and others.
  - American Council on Education, 1969; 9 items (Box 2)
    Survey on graduate education.
  - American Ethnological Society, 1954-1971; 6 items (Box 2)
    Meetings, dues, newsletter.
  - American Indian Historical Society, 1967; 3 items (Box 2)
    Asking FGL to serve on the editorial board of The Indian Historian.
  - American Philosophical Society, 1949-1993; 31 items (Box 2)
    Return of Anthony F. C. Wallace's Tuscarora notebook; obtaining copy of FGL's Oneida materials; publication of Archiquette's Oneida diary by the APS; recording of the Iroquois condolence ceremony chanted by George Thomas; grants; current status of American Indian studies; Onondaga recordings; manuscript review; FGL's membership in APS; asking FGL to serve on the Phillips Fund Committee of the APS; committee meetings.
  - American Scandinavian Foundation, The, 1979-1980; 5 items (Box 2)
    Evaluating applications for awards.
  - American Society for Ethnohistory, 1971; 3 items (Box 2)
    Annual meeting.
  - Amith, Jonathan D., 1979-1991, n.d.; 5 items (Box 2)
    Recommendation; Amith's work on Nahuatl in Mexico; kinship.
  - Amram, David W., Jr., 1957; 3 items (Box 2)
    Availability of grammars in several Native American languages of Mexico.
  - Anderson, Lloyd B., 1984; 2 items (Box 2)
    Etymologies of Mayan calendrical and astronomical terms.
  - Anderson, Myrdene, 1969-1983; 31 items (Box 2)
    NSF research grant application; archaeoastronomy; job applications; abstracts of papers given.
  - Anderson, Philip C., 1979; 1 item (Box 2)
    The meaning of the placename "Coxsackie".
  - Annan, Noel, 1968; 3 items (Box 2)
    The future of the Anthropology Department at University College London.
  - Antal, Laszlo, 1964; 2 items (Box 2)
    Possibly reprinting FGL's article "A Semantic Analysis of the Pawnee Kinship Usage."
  - Antilla, Raimo, n.d.; 1 item (Box 2)
    A hand written note on a ditto copy of "Chapter 16, Classification of Languages" requesting that FGL check Oneida data for accuracy.
  - Arata, Luis O., 1993; 1 item (Box 2)
    Popol Vuh; interpretation of Maya glyphs.
  - Archiquette, Oscar H., 1939-1966; 24 items (Box 2)
    Includes letters and postcards, most in Oneida, and 3 photographs.
  - Arostegui, Carlos, 1978; 2 items (Box 2)
    Dissertation outline for the study of Mixtec names.
  - Athayde, Austregasilo de, et al., 1992; 2 items (Box 2)
    Waimiri-Atroari education program. In Portuguese.
  - Atkins, John, 1962-1964; 3 items (Box 2)
    Atkins' work on Omaha kinship systems; offprints.
  - Austerlitz, Robert, 1965-1967; 4 items (Box 2)
    Invitations to speak at linguistics seminars at Columbia University.
  - Aveni, Anthony F., 1972-1991; 24 items (Box 2)
    Astro-archaeology; archaeoastronomy; Bonampak astronomical evidence; Maya hieroglyphs.
  - Ayala, Maricela, 1980; 5 items (Box 2)
    Invitation to participate in a session on Mayan epigraphy at a meeting on Mayan languages. In Spanish.
  - Bach, Emmon, 1964; 1 item (Box 2)
    Invitation to speak at the Linguistics Club, University of Texas.
  - Ballard, W. L., 1966-1967; 6 items (Box 2)
    Loundsbury's paper on Shanghaiese.
  - Barbeau, Marius, 1941-1964; 12 items (Box 2)
    FGL's work on Oneida, Cherokee, and Wyandot; Barbeau's materials on Cayuga and Tuscarora. Includes an inventory of materials on Huron-Iroquois and Algonkian in the Archives du Seminaire de Quebec.
  - Barber, Elizabeth, 1974-1975; 2 items (Box 2)
    Requesting a copy of a paper FGL gave at LSA. Sending a copy of her paper on voice (enclosure missing).
  - Bardawil, Lawrence W., 1974; 1 item (Box 2)
    Requesting a recommendation to enter special study on Maya gestures.
  - Barrau, Jacques, n.d.; 1 item (Box 2)
    Botanical names and descriptions of several kinds of wood from Brazil.
  - Basehart, Harry W., 1941-1962; 33 items (Box 2)
    Oneida language, medicine-compounding, false faces, [Oneida] hymnbooks, Cherokee language, Oneida WPA projects, Creek busk or green corn dance and other activities on the Oklahoma reservation, Oneida prayers.
  - Bassie, Karen, 1986; 3 items (Box 2)
    Identification of figures the "Group of the Cross at Palenque."
  - Basso, Keith H., 1965-1979; 3 items (Box 2)
    Application of semantic theory to anthropological problems; ethnographic study of Western Apache placenames.
  - Bauman, James, 1974; 3 items (Box 2)
    Postdoctoral study in social anthropology from a background in linguistics.
  - Beals, Ralph L., 1951-1971; 4 items (Box 2)
    FGL's service as LSA liaison to AAA and on the Committee on American Native Languages.
  - Beatty, John, 1972-1973, n.d.; 7 items (Box 2)
    Beatty's dissertation, conference on second language acquisition, job possibilities.
  - Beaux, Nathalie, 1987; 1 item (Box 2)
    Egyptian hieroglyphic writing.
  - Becks, D., 1985; 1 item (Box 2)
    Componential analysis in FGL's work. Includes a 5-page questionaire.
  - Behrman, Carolyn, 1990; 1 item (Box 2)
    History of relations between physical and cultural anthropology.
  - Belshaw, Cyril S., 1983; 2 items (Box 2)
    Asking FGL to referee an article by Alphonso H. Feng, "On the Ordering of the Signs of the North Semitic Theory" (included).
  - Benda, Henry J., 1964; 2 items (Box 2)
    Publication of Mrs. Ihromi-Simatupang's M.A. thesis on the Batak.
  - Bennett, David, 1967; 1 item (Box 2)
    Bennett's paper on the phoneme, taking courses at the University of Michigan.
  - Bennett, Wendell C., 1941-1952, n.d.; 4 items (Box 2)
    FGL's work on Oneida and comparative Iroquoian, studying anthropology, and plans to apply to Yale.
  - Benson, Elizabeth P., 1977-1984, n.d.; 5 items (Box 2)
    FGL's appointment as visiting scholar at Dumbarton Oaks, Palenque rubbings, conference on "The Beginnings of Maya Iconography."
  - Berlin, Brent, 1963-1967; 6 items (Box 2)
    Work on Tzeltal, decipherment of Maya hieroglyphs, classifiers. Includes a letter from Berlin to Morris Swadesh regarding color categories.
  - Bernstein, Howard B., 1963-1997; 17 items (Box 2)
    Bernstein's course schedule, recommendations, fieldwork proposal.
  - Berry, Alison, 1979; 1 item (Box 2)
    Her visit to Palenque. Includes a color photograph.
  - Berry, Jack, 1968; 3 items (Box 2)
    A special issue of IJAL in memory of Hans Wolff.
  - Berwick, Rachel, 1996, n.d.; 2 items (Box 2)
    Gilis book, a wish list of phrases (enclosures missing).
  - Beukema, Ron, 1972-1973, n.d.; 21 items (Box 2)
    Quechua phonology and morphology, Proto-Quechua consonants. Includes term papers, dissertation proposal, and possibly parts of dissertation.
  - Bick, John, 1996; 2 items (Box 2)
    Personal greetings. Includes "Full Circle" by John Bick, Barb Cranford and Lois McNevin: English verse in haiku no renga (Japanese) verse form.
  - Biedermann, Hans, 1962-1969; 4 items (Box 2)
    Compiling a complete corpus of Maya inscriptions, Ferdinand Anders, Das Pantheon der Maya.
  - Bierhorst, John, 1977; 2 items (Box 2)
    A Cherokee lullaby.
  - Biese, Leo P., n.d.; 1 item (Box 2)
    Subscription to Mexicon.
  - Biographical Dictionary of Speech, 1974; 5 items (Box 2)
    Entries on Horatio Hale and John W. Powell for The Biographical Dictionary of the Phonetic Sciences.
  - Bishop, Morris, 1958-1961; 8 items (Box 2)
    The Indians of Hochelaga (Montreal, Quebec), FGL's paper on Cherokee-Iroquoian linguistic relationships
  - Black, Eugene C., 1971; 2 items (Box 3)
    Asking FGL to serve on the committee to evaluate the Anthropology Department at Brandeis University.
  - Black, Glenn A., 1949-1951; 4 items (Box 3)
    FGL's membership in The Society for American Archaeology.
  - Black, Lydia, 1971; 3 items (Box 3)
    Gilyak kinship.
  - Black, Mary, 1968; 1 item (Box 3)
    FGL's paper at AAA Plenary Session.
  - Blau, Harold, 1963-1967; 8 items (Box 3)
    Recording in Onondaga of Handsome Lake's Code, meeting at an Iroquois conference; copies of recent JAF articles, work on Onondaga. Enclosures missing.
  - Blin-Lagarde, Pierrette, 1971-1975; 2 items (Box 3)
    Application for a Killam scholarship.
  - Blinco, Tom and Lila, 1962; 1 item (Box 3)
    Their work in Venezuela.
  - Bloch, Bernard, 1954-1963; 9 items (Box 3)
    Dissertation proposal of J. C. Street, an article by Pierce, the Linguistic Institute, Yale's undergraduate linguistics program, an article by [Dell] Hymes, foreign language requirements.
  - Bloomfield, Leonard, 1941; 5 items (Box 3)
    Alternative forms for Oneida numerals, collection of Oneida materials, FGL's work on Oneida.
  - Blueye, Esther, 1981; 1 item (Box 3)
    Willingness of Maryanne [Mithun] Williams to work with her.
  - Blumensath, H., 1978; 4 items (Box 3)
    Permission to reprint FGL's article, "A Semantic Analysis of the Pawnee Kinship Usage."
  - Bo, Carlo, 1973-1989; 11 items (Box 3)
    Seminars and colloquia organized by the Centro Internazionale di Semiotica e Linguistica, Urbino, Italy. Mostly in French, some Italian.
  - Bodman, Nicholas C., 1964-1965; 4 items (Box 3)
    FGL's article on the Shanghai dialect.
  - Boggs, S. Whittemore, 1952-1953; 8 items (Box 3)
    Boggs' paper "An Atlas of Ignorance: A Needed Stimulus to Honest Thinking and Hard Work," proposal to create maps showing the adequacy of knowledge in various fields around the world.
  - Boggs, Stephen T., 1962-1964; 5 items (Box 3)
    Teaching English as a foreign language, abstracts of papers (enclosures missing), FGL to be nominated to Executive Board of AAA.
  - Bohannan, Paul, 1963-1967; 7 items (Box 3)
    Republishing early classics in anthropology, request to reprint FGL's "The Structural Analysis of Kinship"
  - Bolton, Ralph, 1972; 5 items (Box 3)
    FGL's ICA paper "Some Aspects of the Inca Kinship System," being a discussant for a proposed symposium on Andean kinship.
  - Bonnemete, Pascole, 1 item (Box 3)
    Requesting a meeting with FGL to discuss Maya glyphs.
  - Bonvillain, Nancy L., 1970-1975; 10 items (Box 3)
    Grant applications and references.
  - Bowles, John H., 1989; 1 item (Box 3)
    Selection of a Cherokee word to name a nature conservancy. Includes a map showing the location of the conservancy.
  - Bowman, J. K., 1962; 12 items (Box 3)
    FGL's article "Linguistics and Psychology."
  - Brenner, Edgar H., 1969-1985; 4 items (Box 3)
    Brenner's trip to Guatemala; Maya hieroglyphs.
  - Brew, J. O. and Evelyn N., 1966-1970; 11 items (Box 3)
    FGL's talk at the Peabody Museum, Harvard; FGL's manuscripts for publication.
  - Bright, William, 1965-1969; 3 items (Box 3)
    Reviews of books by Malinowski and Greenberg
  - Brockman, L., 1980; 1 item (Box 3)
    Brockman's interest in studying Maya hieroglyphs.
  - Bromley, Myron, 1967-1996, n.d.; 34 items (Box 3)
    Bromley's graduate work in anthropology and linguistics at Yale; kinship terms in Lower Grand Valley Dani of West Irian (Indonesia); the Bromleys' missionary work in Indonesia. Includes a photo of the Bromley family [1982].
  - Brotherston, J. Gordon, 1983; 3 items (Box 3)
    FGL's manuscript on Maya dates.
  - Brown University, The John Carter Brown Library, 1966; 1 item (Box 3)
    Preparation for publication of the Spanish-Maya part of a Motul dictionary.
  - Bruner, Edward M., 1957-1969; 15 items (Box 3)
    Southeast Asia Program at Yale; Batak kinship; proposed session on "Methods of Formal Analysis in Anthropology" for AAA; Batak dictionaries; fieldwork in Indonesia.
  - Bucca, Salvador, 1958-1967; 11 items (Box 3)
    Bucca's application to Yale; suggested courses; invitation to FGL to teach a course in Buenos Aires, Argentina.
  - Buchler, Ira R., 1963-1966; 7 items (Box 3)
    Buchler's work on a comparative study of Crow terminological systems; Nahuatl kinship terms and pronouns.
  - Buckman, Rev. Winfield, 1950, n.d.; 3 items (Box 3)
    FGL's fieldwork in Brazil. Include a pamphlet on the South America Indian Mission, Inc.
  - Buettner-Janusch, John, 1959-1984; 8 items (Box 3)
    Buettner-Janusch's fieldwork in Kenya; Anthropology at Duke University; invitation to FGL to speak at New York University; his conviction for unnamed crimes and his responses to published statements.
  - Burkenroad, David C., 1968; 1 item (Box 3)
    Burkenroad's Yale experience and the possibility of returning to Yale as a student.
  - Burling, Robbins, 1967-1969; 5 items (Box 3)
    Request for a copy of FGL's Pawnee paper (1956); Tibeto-Burman kinship.
  - Burnaby, Barbara, 1983; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 3)
  - Burns, Donald H., 1958; 2 items (Box 3)
    Translation into Spanish of an article on Quechua structure by Masako Lounsbury.
  - Buser, C. A., 1966; 2 items (Box 3)
    Buser's proposed study of Wyandot and comparison with Mohawk.
  - Bush, Archie C., 1968; 2 items (Box 3)
    Latin kinship terms as a possible dissertation topic.
  - Butt, Audrey, et al., 1952-1956; 22 items (Box 3)
    A manuscript dictionary of Akawaio found among the effects of a Mr. Kenswil; editing and publishing the dictionary; Butt's work among the Akawaio.
  - Calderon, Hector M., n.d.; 2 items (Box 3)
    Publications on Maya hieroglyphs; research on Maya-Yucatec and related languages.
  - Cambridge University Press, 1979-1990, n.d.; 9 items (Box 3)
    Various publications; publication of proceedings of Oxford Conference on Archaeoastronomy in the New World: American Primitive Astronomy. Includes part of draft of FGL's "Astronomical Knowledge at Bonampak."
  - Cameron, Constance P., 1971; 1 item (Box 3)
    Meaning of place-name kenta-ke, possibly of Iroquoian origin.
  - Campbell, Lyle, 1974-1980; 7 items (Box 3)
    Bibliography of Mayan linguistics and languages; Maya hieroglyphs conference.
  - Campisi, Jack, 1971-1973; 9 items (Box 3)
    An Oneida consultant for a course FGL was teaching; Campisi's work on Oneida; teachings of Handsome Lake.
  - Cardoso de Oliveira, Roberto, 1965; 7 items (Box 3)
    Fieldwork in Brazil by Zarko Levak. 2 items in Portuguese.
  - Carlson, John B., 1976-1985; 7 items (Box 3)
    Carlson's post-doctoral fellowship; publication of Archaeoastronomy.
  - Carneiro, Robert L., 1953-1966; 5 items (Box 3)
    Carneiro's proposed work in Brazil; FGL's work in Brazil.
  - Carr, Elizabeth, 1953-1959; 4 items (Box 3)
    Nomination of Charles Hockett as Carnegie Visiting Professor at the University of Hawaii.
  - Carroll, Vern, 1959; 1 item (Box 3)
    Carroll's experience as an anthropologist teaching in England.
  - Carter, Anthony T., 1970-1971; 6 items (Box 3)
    Marathi kinship and Dravidian kinship systems in general.
  - Carter, George F., 1947; 1 item (Box 3)
    Possible pre-Columbian contacts between Central Mexico and Eastern United States.
  - Casagrande, Joseph B., 1940-1966; 25 items (Box 3)
    Casagrande's work in Oklahoma on Comanche and the relationship between language and culture with George Herzog; whispered vowels in Oneida; language and acculturation; FGL's work in Oklahoma on Cherokee; Committee on Linguistics and Psychology, Social Science Research Council.
  - Castillo, Leon Lourie, 1952; 2 items (Box 3)
    suggested study materials for Quechua and Aymara.
  - Caufield, Monica, 1969; 3 items (Box 3)
    FGL's intellectual career.
  - Cayuga Museum of History and Art, Cayuga County Historical Society, 1966-1979, n.d.; 24 items (Box 3)